来看看这两栋楼。
Take a look at these two buildings.
请问，哪栋更高？
Now, which is taller?
如果你选右边那栋，那你猜错了。
If you guess the one on the right, you'd be wrong.
好吧，换个简单点的。就这两栋。
Okay, how about an easier one? These two.
猜猜看？
Any guesses?
答案当然是伍尔沃斯大厦。
It is, of course, the Lotwell Tower.
不过，如果我们按可用楼层高度来算，那就是这栋了。
Although, if we took it to the usable height, then it would be this one.
困惑吗？
Confused?
你该困惑的。
You should be.
你看，世界上那些最高的建筑，其实都没有表面看起来那么简单。
You see, the world's tallest buildings aren't all they seem.
因为几十年来，
Because for decades now,
建筑师们一直在用一套非常聪明的技巧，
architects have been using a very clever set of tricks
在高度数字上大做文章。
to juice the heights of the world's tallest buildings.
而随着我们星球上下一座最高建筑迎来第100层楼板的施工，
And as the next tallest building on our planet
我们不禁想问：它实际上到底有多高？
marks the construction of its 100th floor,
it got us thinking, how big will it actually be?
于是，我们挑选了六栋在高度规则上玩到极致的摩天楼，
So, we've picked six skyscrapers
来搞清楚"最高建筑"究竟意味着什么。
that really stretch the rules of height
to find out what tallest building actually means.
首先，送给所有千禧一代的经典一弹。
First off, here's one for all you millennials out there.
双峰塔（石油双塔）。
The Patronis Towers.
如今它可能有点被遗忘了，但天啊，真是满满的回忆杀。
They're a bit of a forgotten giant nowadays, but man, what a nostalgia trip.
肖恩·康纳利和凯瑟琳·泽塔-琼斯在里面玩起了攀岩。
Shan Connory and Katherine Zeta Jones used them as a jungle gym.
它出现在电视游戏里，
They were in video games
还在一部完全没必要拍的《独立日》续集里被炸掉过。
and they even got dropped on London in a completely unnecessary sequel to Independence Day.
>> 他们就喜欢盯着地标下手。
>> They like to get the landmarks.
>> 但比这一切更重要的是，
>> But more than any of that,
双峰塔曾是1998年到2004年间世界上最高的建筑。
the Patronis Towers were the world's tallest building from 1998 to 2004.
这对马来西亚人民来说，是无比自豪的时刻。
It was a huge moment of pride for the people of Malaysia.
但并非所有人都这么高兴。
But not everyone was so happy.
你看，被它挤下第二名的，
You see, the building it relegated into second place
正是威利斯大厦（西尔斯大厦）——当年还叫西尔斯大厦呢。
was this, the Willis Tower,
or the Sears Tower as it was called back then.
它自1974年起稳坐头把交椅，
It had held the top spot since 1974,
芝加哥人觉得自己被抢了，因为问题就在这里。
and Chicagoans were feeling a bit robbed
because see the problem.
>> 你可能觉得，高度是从这根天线顶端量的，或者至少从这个屋顶顶端量的。
>> Now, you might think the height is measured to the top of the antenna here, or at least the top of the roof here.
不管哪种算法，威利斯大厦都赢了，
Either way, the Willis Tower wins,
对吧？错。
right? Wrong.
大错特错——
So wrong,
事实上，1996年，就在双峰塔即将竣工之际，
in fact, that in 1996, as the Patronus Towers were nearing completion,
一群怒火中烧的芝加哥记者要求讨个说法。
a delegation of incensed Chicago journalists demanded an answer.
于是他们去找了官方最高建筑名单的守护者——
So they went to the keepers of the official list of tallest buildings,
高层建筑与城市人居委员会，
the Council on Tall Buildings and Urban Habitat,
如今已改名为垂直城市化委员会。
now renamed to the Council on Vertical Urbanism.
>> 来自遥远土地的陌生人，昔日的旧友。
>> Strangers from distant lands, friends of old.
>> 对，就是那种感觉。
>> Yeah, exactly that sort of thing.
总之，尽管抗议声四起，委员会的立场非常明确。
Anyway, despite all the protests, the council was perfectly clear.
建筑高度，历来
Buildings are and always have been
都是从地面
measured from the street level
量到建筑的建筑学顶端。
up to the architectural top of the building.
威利斯大厦顶部的那些天线，
These antennas on top of the Willis Tower
与建筑的结构或建筑学意义毫无关系。
have nothing to do with the architecture or the structure of the building.
它们是建成后加装的电视信号塔，从来都没有算进楼高里。
They're TV masts that were added on after it was built, and they were never included in its height.
而双峰塔顶部的尖塔虽然不具备实际功能，却是建筑设计的刻意组成部分，
These spires on top of the patronis tower on the other hand
因此将总高度提升到了451.9 m。
don't serve a function
but they are a deliberate architectural feature of the building
因此将总高度提升到了451.9 m。
and as such
they take the overall height to 451.9 m.
对于任何想在地球上最高建筑里买顶层豪宅的人——我只是随便想想——
Great news for anyone who and I'm just spitboarding here
这可是个好消息。
wanted to buy a penthouse in the tallest building on earth.
这样的顶层豪宅可能长这样。这里放几把椅子。
A penthouse that could look like this. A few chairs over here.
客卧。套间浴室。
Guest bedroom. Onsuite bathroom.
嗯，差不多了。哦，等等。
Yeah, that'll do. Oh, sorry.
我得说，这并不是真正的顶层豪宅。
I should say this isn't the actual penthouse.
只是我用Rayon Design自己设计的一个方案。
It's just one I've designed myself using Rayon Design.
各位建筑师和室内设计师，Rayon Design是专为2026年工作方式打造的新一代CAD平台。
For all you architects and interior designers out there,
Rayon Design is the next generation CAD platform
各位建筑师和室内设计师，Rayon Design是专为2026年工作方式打造的新一代CAD平台。
that's been designed to fit the way you want to work in 2026.
它完全基于网页端，
It's fully web- based,
所以整个团队可以实时在同一个模型上协作。
so your entire team can work off the same model
in real time.
比如我需要一张桌子的CAD块，
If I need a CAD block of a desk, for example,
直接在他们5万个块的资源库里搜一下，
I can just search their library of 50,000 blocks
几秒钟就能放进我的设计里。
and place it in my design in seconds.
如果效果不够理想，
And if it's not quite right,
借助Rayon的AI功能，
I can create my own in no time at all,
我还能随时创建专属的自定义块。
thanks to Rayon's AI feature.
我用Rayon Design设计了一套豪华顶层套房，
I've used Rayon Design to create a fancy penthouse,
不过你完全可以用它做各种商业或住宅项目。
but you can use it for any kind of commercial or residential project.
我真心推荐Rayon，
I seriously rate Rayon
因为它把你需要的一切都整合在一个统一平台里。
because it does everything you need in one unified platform.
精确的技术图纸、
precise technical drawings,
专业的客户展示方案，
stylized client presentations, even procurement,
甚至采购管理，全部通过单一数据源模型保持同步。
all stay synchronized through its single source of truth model.
不过别只听我说。
But don't just take my word for it.
如果你想提升工作效率，
If you want to step up your workflow
同时支持我们继续制作这些精彩视频，
and help us to continue to make these awesome videos,
就点击下方链接或扫描屏幕上的二维码，今天就免费试用Rayon Design吧。
then click the link below or scan the QR code on screen
to try out Round Design for yourself for free today.
规矩就是规矩，
Now, rules are rules,
但那场风波实在太大，
but the whole episode caused such a stink
委员会不得不为摩天楼的高度测量引入两套额外标准。
that the council introduced two additional sets of criteria
for measuring the height of skyscrapers.
最高建筑的桂冠
The coveted tallest building award
依然归属建筑高度最高者，
would still go to the one with the highest architectural height,
但同时还会记录最高有人居住楼层和建筑整体最高点这两项数据。
but a record would also be kept of the highest occupied floor
and the highest point of anything connected to the building.
然而，这不但没有平息争议，反而只是个开始。
But instead of settling the matter, that was just the start.
排在第二位的是默迪卡118大厦。
In at number two is Medca 118.
就在吉隆坡双峰塔的对面，近在咫尺。
Just a stones throw across Koala Lumpa from the Petronis Towers.
2024年竣工时，
When it completed in 2024,
它作为全球第二高建筑跻身排行榜，
it entered the rankings as the world's second tallest building,
把中国的上海中心大厦挤到了第三位。
nudging China's Shanghai Tower down to third.
中国网友对此出奇地淡定。
And Chinese commentators were surprisingly fine with that.
>> 我开玩笑的。
>> I'm kidding.
他们气得要命。
They were absolutely furious.
>> 好吧，又来了。
>> Okay, here we go again.
这是默迪卡118大厦，这是上海中心大厦。
This is Medca 118. And this is the Shanghai Tower.
多亏了那根尖塔，
Thanks to that spire,
默迪卡以678.9 m的总高度力压上海中心大厦。
Medca tops out
at a neat 678.9 m, blasting past the Shanghai Tower.
这是不是真的有点过分了？
Surely this is really pushing it.
默迪卡的最高楼层位于这里，
The highest floor in Medca is here,
刚刚超过500 m。
just above 500 m up.
上海中心大厦的餐厅在120层，
The Shanghai Tower has a restaurant on floor 120,
比这还高出50多米。
over 50 m higher.
如果两座楼并排而立，
If the two were next to each other,
你完全可以坐在上海中心大厦的餐厅里，
you could literally have lunch in the Shanghai Tower
俯视默迪卡118的屋顶。
and look down on the roof of Medca 118.
然而，那栋楼在官方认定上反而"更高"。
And yet, that building would be taller.
听起来很奇怪，但同样的规则在这里适用。
Well, as strange as it sounds, the same rules apply.
默迪卡的尖塔在建筑上是整体设计不可分割的一部分。
Medca's spire is architecturally integral to the building.
不过，我们其实有一个专有名词来形容这类现象——虚高（vanity height）。
But we do actually have a term for things like this, vanity height.
从最高可用楼层
Measure from the highest occupiable floor
量到建筑顶端，这段距离就是虚高。
to the architectural peak of the building
and you have its vanity height.
虚高有各种形态和尺寸。
Vanity height can come in all shapes and sizes.
如今，几乎没有哪座摩天楼没有虚高——
And today almost no skyscraper would be seen without one,
上海中心大厦也不例外，
including the Shanghai Tower,
其建筑顶端比最高可用楼层高出48 m。
whose architectural tip sits 48 m above its highest usable floor.
不过，这跟默迪卡相比简直小巫见大巫——
Although that's nothing compared to Medca,
默迪卡的虚高高达176 m。
which has a whopping 176 m of vanity height.
一座建筑出现虚高有很多原因，
Now there are a lot of reasons why a building might have some vality heights
而默迪卡这根尖塔，背后有它独特的历史意义。
and medas is very particular.
那独特的尖塔造型，
That unusual position of the spire
呼应了马来西亚国父1957年宣告独立（默迪卡）时的标志性剪影。
refers to the iconic silhouettes
of the country's founder
呼应了马来西亚国父1957年宣告独立（默迪卡）时的标志性剪影。
as he declared independence or meda back in 1957.
"虚高"这个名字听起来不太好听，
Vanity Heights isn't the most flattering name
你可能会觉得这是在"作弊"。
and you might well see it as a way of cheating the height of a building.
但默迪卡的支持者们会有完全不同的看法。
But Medca's advocates would think the opposite.
在他们眼里，这完全合理，
they'd see it as completely legitimate
是铭记国家历史重要时刻的一种方式。
and as a way of marking a really foundational moment in their nation's history.
不管你怎么看，
Now, regardless of what you might think of that,
有一点是明确的：
what is clear
这已经和双峰塔那46 m的尖塔完全不是一个量级了。
is that we're in a completely different ballgame to the Petronis Towers
and their 46 m spires.
这背后，是摩天楼存在意义的深层转变。
That's down to a bigger shift in what skyscrapers are for.
要理解这一点，我们得去迪拜看看——
But to get to the bottom of that,
那里有全世界最"虚荣"的建筑：哈利法塔。
we need to head to Dubai,
home to the world's vainest building, the Burj Khalifa.
顺便一提，《独立日》也炸掉过它。
Fun fact, that also got dropped onto London in Independence Day, too.
他们就喜欢盯着地标下手。
They like to get the lands.
>> 毫无疑问，
>> Now, there's no doubt
无论用哪种标准衡量，这都是地球上最高的建筑。
that by any measure,
this is the tallest building on the planet.
它轻松包揽三项桂冠：
It comfortably wins the triple crown
建筑高度、顶点高度和最高可用楼层高度。
for architectural heights,
height, tip, and highest occupiable floor.
从设备层到尖塔顶端，
And with a gap of 242 m between this mechanical floor
差距高达242 m，
and the tip of the spire,
哈利法塔因此保持着地球上任何建筑中最大虚高的纪录。
the Burj Khalifa holds the record
for the biggest vanity heights of any building on Earth.
事实上，如果只把这一部分建筑移植到曼哈顿，
In fact, if you took just this part of the building and planted it in Manhattan,
它依然会主宰纽约的天际线。
it would still dominate the New York skyline.
但这其实有些偏离重点，
But that really kind of misses the point
因为摩天楼早已不只是一栋建筑那么简单。
because skyscrapers have become so much more
than buildings.
最初的摩天楼是为了满足实际需求
The first skyscrapers were born out of necessity,
而诞生的——
rising in crowded cities
在寸土寸金的拥挤城市里，
where buildings invariably had to make the most
建筑不得不往上发展，充分利用那一小块地皮。
of the small plots of land they usually found themselves rising on.
但回到2000年代哈利法塔建设之际，
But if we rewind to the 2000s when the Burj Cleer was being built,
迪拜还不是一座熙熙攘攘的大都市，
Dubai wasn't yet a bustling metropolis.
根本没有土地稀缺的问题。
There was no land scarcity.
那时的迪拜只是一个人口稀少、高度依赖自然资源的宁静港口小城。
This was a quiet, sparssely populated port with an overdependence on natural resources.
它建摩天楼，
It didn't start building skyscrapers
不是因为缺地。
because of a lack of land.
而是为了把自己变成一座繁华的大都市——
it started building them
在那之后，摩天楼在这里才真正站得住脚。
to become a big thriving metropolis
where nowadays skyscrapers make a lot more sense.
进入2000年代，
As the 2000s rolled on,
城市越能建出高耸炫目的楼，就越有面子。
the bigger and flashier
the city could build, the better.
这座巨塔的拔地而起引领了这股风潮，
Following the lead of this enormous tower,
成为一个转折点——
it was a watershed moment,
不仅对迪拜，对整个摩天楼行业而言皆然。
not just for Dubai,
but for skyscrapers in and of themselves.
这张图表显示了超高层摩天楼的虚高数量与规模变化趋势。
This chart shows the amount and size of Vanity heights on super tall skyscrapers.
这里是双峰塔，这里就是之后发生的一切。
Here are the Petronis Towers and here is what happened after that.
而最关键的，是这些建筑中来自迪拜的那些。
But most importantly of all these buildings, these are the ones in Dubai.
迪拜以前所未有的方式，
What Dubai did was leverage
将摩天楼的魅力发挥到了极致。
the allure of skyscrapers
to an extent that no one had ever really done before.
而引领这一切的，正是哈利法塔。
And leading all that was the Burj Khalifa.
是的，它过于张扬了。
Yes, it was excessive.
是的，它有点虚荣，但它成功了。
Yes, it's quite vain, but it worked.
摩天楼并不总是只有办公空间。
Skyscrapers aren't always just office space.
它们有时也能成为软实力的象征，
They can sometimes become symbols
并在这个案例中帮助重塑了整个国家的形象。
of soft power too
and in this case help reinvent an entire country.
它开创了一个"每一米都在较劲"
It created a world of appearances
的时代，从此摩天楼再也不同以往。
where every meter mattered
and skyscrapers would never be the same again.
话说回来，迪拜还有另一栋建筑——Index塔。
Now to be fair, Dubai is also home to this, the Index.
它是一座超高层建筑，坐落在迪拜。
It's a super tall. It's in Dubai.
顶层楼板与建筑顶点之间仅有4 m的差距，
And with just four meters separating
因此它也保持着另一项纪录——
its top floor with the building's peak,
300 m以上摩天楼中虚高最小的建筑，虚高仅占整体高度的1%。
it also holds the record for the smallest vanity height of any skyscraper
above 300 m, measuring
300 m以上摩天楼中虚高最小的建筑，虚高仅占整体高度的1%。
just 1% of its overall structure.
这是不是推翻了我们刚才说的一切？也许是。也许不是。
Now, does that contradict everything we've just said? Possibly. Yes. No.
我也不知道。
I Who knows?
这个问题留给评论区吧。
That is one for the comment section.
虚高的爆炸式增长或许是近代才有的现象，
The explosion in Vanity Heights might be a recent phenomenon,
但比高的竞赛从来就没公平过。
but the battle to build big has never been a fair fight.
这就引出了我们的第四座楼——克莱斯勒大厦。
That brings us to number four, the Chrysler building.
摩天楼和灾难片之间真的有些缘分，不是吗？
There's just something about skyscrapers and disaster movies, isn't there?
好吧，先把迪拜放一边。
Anyway, forget Dubai for now.
时间倒回一百年，
Wind back a 100red years
当曼哈顿似乎找到了无限的金钱密码，
and the original race for the skies was steaming ahead in Manhattan
一场最初的登天竞赛正在岛上如火如荼地上演。
after the island seemed to have found an infinite money hack.
争夺世界最高摩天楼头衔的竞争极其激烈。
competition to hold the prize of the world's tallest skyscraper was intense.
1929年，当时最难被超越的，就是伍尔沃斯大厦。
And in 1929, the one to beat was this, the Woolworth building.
沃尔特·克莱斯勒正全力打造一座65层高的装饰艺术风格摩天大楼，
Walter Krysler was busy working on a soaring 65story art deco sky palace
誓要高过周围所有邻居。
that would stand taller than any of its neighbors.
直到乔治·L·奥尔斯特罗姆（George L. Ohrstrom）横空出世。
That was until George L. Or entered the chat.
就在克莱斯勒大厦破土动工不久，
Shortly after ground broke on the Kryser building,
奥尔斯特罗姆计划在几英里之外建一栋47层、略矮一截的楼。
Orstrom come up with a plan for a shorter 47story building.
地点定在40华尔街大厦。
a few miles away at 40 Wall Street.
随后他突然清醒过来，
Then he quickly came to his senses
打响了摩天楼史上最臭名昭著的高度之争的发令枪。
and fired the starting pistol on one of the most infamous rivalries in skyscraper history.
奥尔斯特罗姆大幅加高了自己的塔楼，比克莱斯勒大厦高出9.8 m。
Orstramm jacked up the size of his tower, beating the Krysler building by 9.8 m.
此时克莱斯勒大厦已经在建了，
With construction already well underway,
重新设计后高度定为282 m，
the Krysler building was redesigned to be 282 m high,
这又逼得奥尔斯特罗姆将自己的塔楼加到283 m。我懂，离谱吧？
which prompted Austramm to raise his tower to 283 m. I know, right?
看起来40华尔街大厦胜券在握，
It looked like 40 Wall Street had the edge,
但克莱斯勒还有后招。
but Krysler had a trick up his sleeve.
他的建筑师威廉·范·艾伦（William Van Allen）悄悄获得许可，
His architect, William Van Allen, quietly gained permission
打算在克莱斯勒大厦顶部安装一根38 m的尖塔。
to plant a 38 m spire on top of the Chrysler building.
为了出奇制胜，这根尖塔被秘密建造在屋顶内部。
To complete the subtifuge, the spire was built in secret inside the roof.
1929年10月的一个戏剧性夜晚，
And over the course of a dramatic night in October 1929,
尖塔被吊装固定，安在了新落成的克莱斯勒大厦顶端。
the spire was lifted up and installed on top of the new Chrysler building.
最终高度飙升至319 m，
The final height was taken to a massive 319 m,
彻底碾压了可怜的40华尔街大厦。
dwarfing the puny 40 Wall Street.
沃尔特·克莱斯勒建成了世界上最高的建筑。
Walter Krysler had built the world's tallest building.
但更重要的是，他赢了。
But more importantly, he had won.
但眼红曼哈顿天际线的，不只是奥尔斯特罗姆一人。
But it wasn't just Orm who was looking at Manhattan's skyline with envy.
1920年代，约瑟夫·斯大林正着手重塑莫斯科，他立志打造出堪比美国"山姆大叔"那边炫耀的高大雄伟建筑。
In the 1920s, Joseph Stalin was taking an interest in remodeling Moscow,
and he was determined to build something every bit as tall and grand
1920年代，约瑟夫·斯大林正着手重塑莫斯科，他立志打造出堪比美国"山姆大叔"那边炫耀的高大雄伟建筑。
as Uncle Sam had to brag about over in the US.
这份执念，成就了我们榜单上的第五座楼——
And that determination has given us the number five on this list,
莫斯科的乌克兰大酒店。
the Ukraine Hotel in Moscow.
哈利法塔或许拥有最大的绝对虚高，
The Burj Khalifa might have the biggest overall vanity height,
但这座苏联时代的建筑保持着另一项纪录，
but this Soviet gym holds the record
让它几乎不符合"建筑"的定义。
that nearly stops it from being a building at all.
让我来解释一下。
Let me explain.
乌克兰大酒店是斯大林在莫斯科委托建造的多座摩天楼之一，
The Ukraine Hotel was one of several skyscrapers in Moscow commissioned by Stalin,
也就是今天所说的"七姐妹楼"。
known today as the Seven Sisters.
但如果你看它的平面图，
But if you look at the footprints,
会发现它和你对摩天楼的固有印象非常不同。
it's very different from what you'd expect from a skyscraper.
它不是一个方正的实心体块，
Rather than being a solid block,
而是呈U形向外展开，中间围着一个庭院。
it curves around in a U-shape with a courtyard in the center.
显然，他们不是因为空间不够。
Clearly, they weren't hardressed for space.
据说，这座酒店最初设计的是平屋顶。
Legend has it the hotel was originally designed with a flat roof.
但斯大林不满意。
But Stalin wasn't happy with this.
他抱怨道：美国的摩天楼都有尖塔，我们的也得有。
American skyscrapers have spires, he complained. So should.
于是，为了与酒店整体比例协调，
So in keeping with the proportions of the hotel,
一根73 m高的巨型尖塔被加装在顶部。
a gigantic 73 m spire was added on top.
垂直城市化委员会对摩天楼有非常严格的规定。
Now the Council on Vertical Urbanism has very strict rules on skyscrapers.
至少50%的高度必须是可居住空间。
At least 50% of their height must be occupiable.
否则，它就不是建筑，也不是摩天楼。
Otherwise, it's not a building or a skyscraper.
它是一座塔。
It's a tower.
那根巨大的尖塔加上底座，
That massive spire and the pedestal it sits on
让这座楼的虚高占比高达42%。
gives the tower a whopping vanity height that takes up 42% of the building.
这不仅让乌克兰大酒店成为虚高比例最高的建筑，同时也让它距离"不再算作建筑"的边界，只差一把锤子镰刀的距离。
Not only does that make the Ukraine Hotel
the Venus building by percentage of overall height,
这不仅让乌克兰大酒店成为虚高比例最高的建筑，同时也让它距离"不再算作建筑"的边界，只差一把锤子镰刀的距离。
it also leaves it a hammer and sickle away
from not being a building at all.
不过，如果你的甲方是约瑟夫·斯大林，
Still, if you're an architect and your client is Joseph Stalin,
最好还是照做。
it's best to do what he says.
这就把我们带回到了今天的主角——吉达塔。
And that brings us back, of course, to this, the Jedi Tower.
正如我们在纽约看到的，竞争是推动建筑高度的最大动力。
As we saw in New York, nothing drives heights like competition.
吉达塔的前期工作始于2008年，
It's probably no coincidence then that preliminary work for the Jedha Tower began in 2008,
恰好在邻居哈利法塔开业前后，这或许不是巧合。
just before the neighboring Burj Khalifa opened for business.
哈利法塔最终以828 m的高度矗立在迪拜街头，
While the Burj Khalifa would go on to stand
而吉达塔的最初方案是建造一座1英里高、约1600 m的摩天楼。
828 m above the streets of Dubai,
the original plans for the Jedha Tower were for a 1mile skyscraper
而吉达塔的最初方案是建造一座1英里高、约1600 m的摩天楼。
standing 1,600 m tall.
那个方案很快就被放弃了，因为这纯属异想天开。
That was quickly dropped because it's absolutely insane.
于是他们把英制换成公制，
So, they switched metric for Imperial
改为建造一座1 km高的摩天楼。
and started work on a 1 km tall skyscraper instead.
这座建筑围绕Y形核心筒设计。
The building is designed around a Y-shaped core.
这和哈利法塔以及加拿大国家电视塔等建筑内部采用的结构相同。
That's the same thing you'll see inside the Burj Khalifa
and other structures like the CN Tower.
之所以采用这种设计，是因为它是应对建筑自身极端重量以及风力对外立面产生的巨大横向荷载的最有效方式，
It's used because it's the most effective way for the building to cope
但也只能撑到这一步。
with the extreme weight of itself
and the extraordinary lateral loads created by the wind hitting the building's exterior.
但也只能撑到这一步。
But that only takes it so far.
从167层往上，
From level 167 onwards,
建筑舍弃混凝土核心筒，改用钢结构完成。
the building shuns its concrete core and is being completed in steel.
这个巨型结构内部设有梯子，
This gigantic structure will contain the ladders
供维护人员攀爬至摩天楼最顶端的航空警示灯——
that allow maintenance crews to access the aircraft warning beacons
相当于地面以上240层楼的高度。
at the very top of the skyscraper,
the equivalent of 240 stories above the Earth.
爬那段梯子可不是件轻松的活。
Climbing that ladder won't be an easy job.
虽然没有公布精确数据，
Exact measurements haven't been published,
但根据标准层高估算，
but based on the standard floor height,
吉达塔的尖塔高度可能超过300 m。
the spire of the Jedha Tower could be well over 300 m tall.
这座非凡建筑的虚高，
The vanity height for this extraordinary building
最终可能本身就是一座超高层摩天楼的规模。
might end up being a super tall skyscraper in its own right.
我不是来告诉你该怎么看待虚高，
Now, I'm not here to tell you what to think about vanity height
也不是来评判它是对是错的。
or to decide whether it's right or wrong.
你可能觉得这是好事。
You might think it's a good thing.
你可能觉得这是坏事。
You might think it's a terrible thing.
我觉得更有意思的，是它揭示了我们作为人类的某些本质——
I guess what I find more interesting is what it says about us
因为我们一直都是这样，贯穿整个历史。
and how we build our buildings
because we've always done this right through the ages.
从教堂、寺庙、金字塔，
From cathedrals, temples, pyramids,
到今天我们见到的现代摩天楼，
all the way up to the more modern skyscrapers we see today,
我们始终渴望突破边界。
we've always wanted to break that frontier.
作为人类，我们总想走得更远、飞得更高。
As human beings, we've wanted to go further and higher.
无论驱动我们的是自我、经济利益，
Whether that's out of ego, economic gain,
还是对不朽的渴望，我们始终如一，贯穿时间长河，仰望天际，追问那个问题：
or wanting to be remembered long after we're gone,
"我们究竟能飞多高？"
we've always consistently, right through time, looked up to the skies and asked,
"How high can we really go?"
本期视频由Rayon Design赞助播出。
This video was sponsored by Rayon Design.
别忘了，你可以点击下方链接免费试用Rayon Design。
Don't forget that you can try Rayon Design for free using the link below.
一如既往，各位，如果你喜欢这期视频，
And as always guys, if you enjoyed this video
想持续获取建筑领域的权威内容，
and you want to get more from the definitive video channel for construction,
记得订阅B1M频道。
make sure you're subscribed to the B1M.